Finding Aid for Alan N. Polasky papers, 1955-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Alan N. Polasky papers 1955-1976
Polasky, Alan N., d. 1976
85354 Aa 2
Professor of law at the University of Michigan. Papers include correspondence, speeches, and conference files largely concerning his interest in gift and estate tax law.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
5 linear feet
Donor number 5925.
The collection is open to research.
Alan N. Polasky became a professor of Law at the University of Michigan in 1957. Prior to coming to Michigan Polasky taught law at Northwestern University and practiced privately in Illinois and Iowa Polasky received his J.D. degree from the University of Iowa in 1951. That institution also awarded him a B.S. degree in accounting in 1947. Polasky became a certified public accountant in 1948.
Polasky's greatest areas of legal interest were in rules of evidence and estate law. In the latter he was recognized as a national expert. He spoke widely on the subject, and served as a member or chairman of several American Bar Association committees dealing with various aspects of estate planning. Polasky died suddenly in 1976.
The papers of Alan Polasky divide themselves into six series: Biographical, Correspondence, Professional affiliations, Speeches, Subject files and Material relating to the University of Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Law.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Law School.
- Biographical material
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  The correspondence files, covering the years 1958 through 1976, are arranged chronologically. Apparently duplicate copies of this file were arranged by subject, however much of this material was lost.
  - 1958 (Box 1)
  - 1959 (Box 1)
  - 1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961 (Box 1)
  - 1962, 9 folders (Box 1)
  - 1963, 12 folders (Box 1)
  - 1964, 12 folders (Box 1)
  - 1965, 11 folders (Box 1)
  - 1966, 12 folders (Box 1)
  - 1967, 12 folders (Box 1)
  - 1968, 12 folders (Box 2)
  - 1969, 11 folders (Box 2)
  - 1970, 12 folders (Box 2)
  - 1971, 12 folders (Box 2)
  - 1972, 7 folders (Box 2)
  - 1973, 12 folders (Box 2)
  - 1974, 12 folders (Box 2)
  - 1975, 11 folders (Box 2)
  - 1976 (Box 2)
- Professional affiliations
  Included under "Professional affiliations" are materials relating to the American Bar Association (ABA) in general and its committees regarding "Real Property, Probate and Trust Law" and Taxation in specific. There is also a great deal of information regarding the ABA's Uniform Disposition of Community Property At Death model legislation. The American Bar Foundation and organizations interested in appellate court reform are also represented in this group.
  - American Bar Association
    - Accounting liaison (Box 3)
    - Evidence (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Real Property, Probate and Trust Law
      - 1965 (Box 3)
      - 1972 (Box 3)
      - 1973 (Box 3)
      - 1974 (Box 3)
      - 1975 (Box 3)
    - Taxation
      - Undated (Box 3)
      - 1965, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - 1966, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - 1967 (Box 3)
      - 1968 (Box 3)
      - 1969 (Box 3)
      - 1970 (Box 3)
      - 1971 (Box 3)
      - 1972 (Box 3)
      - 1973 (Box 3)
    - Title Insurance
      - 1966, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - 1967, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Uniform Disposition of Community Property Rights at Death (UDOCPRADA)
      - 1966 (Box 3)
      - 1969 (Box 3)
      - 1970 (Box 3)
      - 1971 (Box 3)
      - 1973 (Box 3)
      - 1976 (Box 3)
  - American Bar Foundation
    - Court procedure (Box 3)
    - Committee on distilled spirits plant supervision (Box 3)
    - Federal tax procedure project
      - 1962 (Box 3)
      - 1963 (Box 3)
      - 1964 (Box 3)
      - 1965 (Box 3)
      - 1966, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - 1967 (Box 3)
      - 1968 (Box 3)
      - 1969 (Box 3)
  - Appellate Court Reform (ACAJ)
    - 1971 (Box 3)
    - 1972, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 3)
  - Chicago Bar Association (Box 3)
  - National conference of commissioners on uniform state laws (Box 3)
- Speeches
  The Speeches series is incomplete. Those speeches which remain cover the years 1959 through 1976. Many of the extant folders contain only summaries or outlines of Polasky's remarks. In some instances there is merely a letter stating the subjects that will be covered.
  - 1959
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - 1960
    - Estate planning (Box 3)
    - Problems of an executor managing insurance (Box 3)
  - 1961
    - Estate Planning Council, St. Louis (Box 3)
  - 1962
    - Estate Planning when a couple moves from a Community Property to a Common Law State (Box 3)
    - Estate Planning, Cleveland (Box 3)
    - Estate Planning, University of Miami
      - Correspondence (Box 3)
      - Planning the Disposition of Life and Employee Benefits Insurance (Box 3)
      - Tax Problems including the use of the Marital Deduction (Box 3)
  - 1963
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Lawyers wives (address before) (Box 4)
    - American Law Institute (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning Council, Birmingham (Box 4)
    - Mid-America Tax Institute, St. Louis (Box 4)
  - 1964
    - American Bankers Association (Box 4)
    - Columbia, South Carolina (Box 4)
  - 1965
    - Estate and Gift taxes (Box 4)
    - Commerce Clearing House (Box 4)
    - Florida Bar Tax Institute (Box 4)
    - University of San Diego (Box 4)
  - 1966
    - Evidence talk for Michigan Judges (Box 4)
    - A.B.A. Southwestern Regional Meeting, San Diego (Box 4)
    - Hackley Bank, Muskegon (Box 4)
    - Harvard Law Society of Philadelphia (Box 4)
    - Instituto Centroamericana, El Salvador (Box 4)
  - 1967
    - Florida Bar (meeting of) (Box 4)
    - Fremont Bank Trust Seminar (Box 4)
    - Institute on Continuing Education for the Illinois Bar (Box 4)
    - Kentucky Tax Institute (Box 4)
    - University of Miami (Box 4)
  - 1968
    - American Bar Association (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning Council, Birmingham (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning Council, Eastern Indiana (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning Council, Southwestern Michigan (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning Council, Tucson (Box 4)
    - Kentucky Tax Institute (Box 4)
    - National Institute on Condemnation, St. Louis (Box 4)
    - State Bank and Trust Co. Seminar, Evanston, Illinois (Box 4)
  - 1969
    - American Bar Association (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning, Pensacola, Florida (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning Council, Central Arizona (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning Council, Tucson (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning Council, Worcester, Ma. (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning Councils, National Association (Box 4)
    - First National Bank of Colorado Springs Seminar University of Miami (Box 4)
    - Multi-state Tax Commission, Special Committee on Income Tax Problems (Box 4)
    - Symposium on Tax Simplification, Durham, North Carolina (Box 4)
    - U.S. House of Representatives, Ways and Means Committee (testimony before) (Box 4)
  - 1970
    - Arizona State Tax Conference (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning, Mackinac Island (Box 4)
    - Illinois Society of Certified Public Accountants (Box 4)
  - 1971
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Louisville, Kentucky (Box 4)
    - University of San Diego (Box 4)
  - 1972
    - American Bankers Association (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning for Farmers (Box 4)
    - National Trust School (Box 4)
  - 1973
    - California Bankers Association (Box 4)
    - University of Cincinnati (Box 4)
    - University of Colorado (Box 4)
    - Kalamazoo chapter, National Association of Accountants (Box 4)
  - 1974
    - Estates and Trusts (Box 4)
    - P.L.I. transcript (Box 4)
  - 1975
    - Estate Planning Council, Central Arizona (Box 4)
    - Estate Planning Council, Minneapolis (Box 4)
    - University of Miami (Box 4)
    - Tulane Tax Institute (Box 4)
  - 1976
    - Bank Marketing Association, San Antonio (Box 4)
    - Colorado Bar Probate Institute (Box 4)
    - University of Miami (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 4)
- Subject file
  The subject file represents material that may have been intended for interfiling elsewhere in the collection, but which was not finished at the time of Polasky's death. It is arranged alphabetically.
  - Certified Public Accountants (Box 5)
  - Corporate Tax Procedures (Box 5)
  - Estate Planning, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Evidence (Box 5)
  - Family Law (Box 5)
  - Inheritance Tax, California (Box 5)
  - Inheritance Tax, Ohio (Box 5)
  - Private Annuities (Box 5)
  - Pooled Income Funds (Box 5)
  - Pour Over Wills (Box 5)
  - Tax Reform, 4 folders (Box 5)
- University of Michigan
  Polasky's University of Michigan material deals primarily with the Law School. It contains a copy of his lectures on estate planning, and also a good deal of information about proposed curriculum changes in the Law School.
  - 1955-1960 (Box 5)
  - 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - 1963
    - Curriculum Committee (Box 5)
    - Leave of Absence (Box 5)
  - 1964
    - Curriculum (Box 5)
    - Fullbright Grant Information (Box 5)
  - 1965
    - Fullbright Grant Information (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - 1966 (Box 5)
    - 1967 (Box 5)
    - 1968 (Box 5)
    - 1969
      - Curriculum (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - 1970 (Box 5)
    - 1971 (Box 5)
    - 1972 (Box 5)
    - 1973 (Box 5)
    - 1975 (Box 5)
    - Lectures re. Estate Planning, 3 folders (Box 5)